<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<APIProxy revision="2" name="camara-kyc-match">
  <DisplayName/>
  <Description>
This API provides the customer with the ability to compare the information it (Service Provider, SP) has for a particular mobile phone user with that on file (and verified) by the mobile phone user's Operator in their own KYC records, in order for the SP to confirm the accuracy of the information and provide a specific service to the mobile phone user.

## Relevant Definitions and concepts

* **KYC**: stands for Know Your Customer and it is the process of a business verifying the identity of their clients and assessing their suitability, along with the potential risks of illegal intentions towards the business relationship.

* **Match Score**: a numerical value that quantifies the similarity between two pieces of text based on the words they contain. This score is often used in various applications like text comparison, plagiarism detection, information retrieval, and natural language processing. The score typically reflects how well the words in one text match the words in another text. In the context of this API, this score will be used to determine how much does the input information looks like the information stored in the Operator's system. Unless otherwise captured in the specification, score will use the Jaro-Winkler distance algorithm for all countries. This parameter, as optional, will be returned depending on the capability of the Operator to calculate the scoring value. This means that not all Operators will implement this functionality or won't have the requested parameter available. It can happen that an Operator implements the score functionality but, for whatever reason, is not able to calculate it based on the client's input or the related stored information. For these cases, the score property related won't be returned in the response.
The range of score values is between "0" and "100", where higher scores indicate a higher similarity between the two compared parameters.

## API Functionality

This API allows API clients to verify the matching of a number of attributes related to a customer identity against the account data bound to their phone number.  The API is intended to be used in the following scenarios, for example:

* To verify the user personal data during the digital registration of an account to a 3rd party service.

* To prevent fraud, wrong or imprecise information, and/or facilitate the onboarding of a mobile phone user to a 3rd party service.

The API supports a multi-level hierarchy of property validation. In addition to the initial verification of the `phoneNumber`, an additional `idDocument` validation may occur based on different Operator requirements. This means that, in those cases, if the value of `idDocument` is not provided or it does not match the one bound to the specific phone number in the Operator systems, the operation will return an error.

The following figure is the generic high-level flows of this API.  


</Description>
  <CreatedAt>1737647395556</CreatedAt>
  <LastModifiedAt>1737648181412</LastModifiedAt>
  <BasePaths>/camara/kyc-match/v0.2</BasePaths>
  <Policies>
    <Policy>OAuthV2-VerifyAccessToken</Policy>
    <Policy>EV-DocumentID</Policy>
    <Policy>RF-MissingIDDcoument</Policy>
    <Policy>JS-VerifyScope</Policy>
    <Policy>RF-InvalidScope</Policy>
  </Policies>
  <ProxyEndpoints>
    <ProxyEndpoint>default</ProxyEndpoint>
  </ProxyEndpoints>
  <Resources>
    <Resource>properties://kyc-match.properties</Resource>
    <Resource>jsc://verify-scope-1.0.js</Resource>
  </Resources>
  <TargetEndpoints>
    <TargetEndpoint>default</TargetEndpoint>
  </TargetEndpoints>
</APIProxy>
